

COLM ROGERS



Address

Groβe Tulln Straβe 22, 3041 Siegersdorf



& Phone

(0043) 660 9591035



colmrogers91@gmail.com

SOCIAL



LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/colmrogers/



Website

https://rogers-

1991.github.io/Portfolio Website/

EDUCATION

Higher Diploma in Science with Computing

Griffith College Dublin 1st Class Honours / 2020 - 2021

Certificate, Diploma, 2 Higher Diplomas and 2 Mixing and **Mastering Awards in** Sound Technology in Music/Film

Academy of Sound Dublin Distinctions / 2016-2018

BA Connect in Film Studies with English and Philosophy

NUI Galway 2nd Class Honours / 2010 - 2015

BA in Film Studies

UC Berkelev 3.67/4 GPA / 2014 - 2014

PROFILE

Hardworking & achievement-oriented student recently graduated with a 1st Class Honours Higher Diploma in Science in Computing. Honours graduate of Film Studies with Arts from NUI Galway. Strong passion for creativity and technical aptitude, with a 2:1 Honours standard in English and writing, organisation and communication skills and a sincere passion for learning more.

Direct project management experience, handling entire post-production process of film projects, through my post-production company, Rogers Sound. Proficient in the use of audio and video software with experience in various departments, both on location and post-production.

WORK HISTORY

Intern Front-End Developer

Brainnest - Remote

05.2022 - Present

- Currently attending front-end development internship online for 4 weeks.
- Assigned to teams to work on one project per week that resembles real projects done in a work environment.
- Primary focus on 3 front-end languages HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Using version control software (Github Desktop) to upload projects each week.
- Will be awarded certificate of completion from Brainnest after internship is finished.

Freelance Front-End Developer

Freelance - Vienna

02.2022 - Present

- Currently working on web application for gifts and interiors shop,
- Responsible for development, testing, responsive design, continuity, and deployment of website.
- Following security protocol standards (SSL) and browser compatibility checks.
- Working on developing a system to help efficiently update stock for products and various brands.
- Using WordPress and various plugins to enhance UI/UX Testing and Design (Meta-Slider, Twentig, Custom Post Type UI), boost and monitor sales (Woo Commerce), and help boost SEO (Yoast).

Other land, and individe laws Coulet and DLID

SOFTWARE

- WordPress
- Avid Pro Tools 10, 11, 12
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Davinci Resolve 14, 15
- Adobe Creative Cloud Suite

LANGUAGES

- Java and JavaFX
- MySQL / PHP
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Tailwind / Bootstrap
- React

INTERESTS





Cooking

Playing Music





Writing

Movies

LANGUAGES

English

Native Speaker

German

Beginner (learning)

QUALITIES

- Creativity
- Flair for writing and the English language
- Strong Work Ethic
- Excellent Communication
- Technical Proficiency
- Strong Problem Solver

WORK HISTORY (continued)

Sound Supervisor, Designer and Editor / Video Editor / Content Creator

Freelance - Dublin

10.2016 - 04.2020

- Supervised entire post-production process of a feature film, including audio, visual, VFX and colour.
- Arranged production meetings and supervised projects sent to different production houses.
- Worked in all audio post-production departments, provided video edit, and supervised Colour, VFX and Music.
- Recorded and mixed sound on-location.
- Created and managed a data library of audio/video files for feature projects.
- Transcoded raw video footage to low-resolution proxies for editing.

Contact Administrator and Customer Care Representative

|11 Ireland - Roscommon

01.2018 - 05.2018 / 01.2019 - 05.2019

- Designed and implemented an application monitoring system, which enabled
 the business to meet its target of completing over 300 outstanding
 applications, while simultaneously managing new applications helping to reach
 all project goals on time.
- Secured over 30 US jobs by meeting and negotiating with owner of Bubba Gump Shrimp in Chicago.
- Contacted US Visa Sponsors and applicants daily regarding completed application forms.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Owner and Founder of freelance Post-Production Company, Rogers Sound
- Designed portfolio website: https://rogers-1991.github.io/Portfolio Website
- Interviewed 2 Academy Award Winners Mark Berger and Walter Murch for final film paper
- Voted Class Rep in Computer Science Course in Griffith College
- Student of HBO screenwriter J. Mira Kopell
- Produced, wrote, and directed short film, Chemical Lover
- Credited on 2 Feature Films
- Only student from John Huston Film School to be accepted into UC Berkeley
- Gave film audio lectures at Filmbase, Dublin
- Built own custom PC

REFEREES

Matt Rogers

Director/Owner of J1 Ireland

Phone (00353) 86 8488792 Email matt@j1ireland.com

Noel Storey

Owner of Beacon Studios

Phone (00353) 167 62474 Email noel@beaconstudios.net